# **LLOYD ARMSTRONG**

# Cloud | DevOps | Big Data

**4** +49 174 5102923

www.lloydarmstrong.dev

- @ lloydarmstrong@gmail.com
- O Düsseldorf, Germany

linkedin.com/in/lloyd-armstrong

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Senior Data Platform Engineer

#### **Metro Markets GmbH**

iii 11/2023 - Present ♥ Düsseldorf, Germany

- Enabling Business Intelligence Analyst and Executives to make critical business decisions by designing, maintaining, and optimizing data pipelines using MySQL, Debezium, Apache Flink and Apache Kafka.
- Working with Apache Impala and Apache Kudu clusters supporting our Power BI environment.

### Cloud DevOps Engineer

iii 11/2022 - 11/2023 ♀ Düsseldorf, Germany

- Reduced Google Cloud costs by 38%
- · Refactored legacy Terraform & implemented customized modules
- Rightsized and refined resource use across multiple projects by using historical usage statistics collected using Grafana and Prometheus observability tools
- Implemented Helm deployments and introduce the use of Argo CD for Kubernetes
- Managed and streamlined GitLab CI/CD pipelines to reduce operational overhead

# **DevOps Automation Engineer**

#### trivago

- Lead embedded DevOps Engineer for 3 teams involved in Business Analytics and TV Advertising.
- Using the Hashicorp tech stack, migrated the entire Trivago Business Analytics platform from monolithic on-premise servers to a highlyavailable, local cloud, using Nomad, Vault, Consul, Levant and Vagrant.
- Reduced time to release by optimizing Jenkins CI/CD pipelines.

### DevOps Engineer

#### **Connect Mobile Communications**

- Migrated 12 monolithic server-based applications to a **Docker** containerized environment using Linux as our Base OS
- Architected and built a Big Data platform from scratch using Elasticsearch and Logstash to process millions of data points daily, graphing in Kibana
- Implemented and managed Development, QA and Production Jenkins pipelines

# Junior DevOps Engineer

### **Panoptix**

- Hands-on startup role: Assembling, Installing and monitoring advanced network analysis devices in secure banking environments.
- Contributed to building a custom application with ELK Stack and Saltstack Experience.

# **EDUCATION**

B. Mus (Honours)

**University of Chichester** 

**#** 2013 - 2016

# SUMMARY

GCP and AWS Certified Engineer with 9 years experience in architecting, maintaining and growing cloud-based platforms and complex software development lifecycles. A musicianturned-tech aficionado, with a passion for automating things and new technologies that make our lives easier.

# CERTIFICATION

#### **AWS Cloud Practitioner**

Amazon Web Services

#### **Cloud Architect Professional Certificate**

Google Cloud Platform

# **SKILLS**

AWS	Google Clou	d Terraform
Kubern	etes & Helm	Docker
Ansible	ElasticSe	arch Kafka
Flink	Gitlab CI/CD	Apache Impala
Grafana	a MySQL	Prometheus
Python	Redis	Apache Kudu

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**



### **Reduced Cloud Costs by 38%**

Within 6 months of joining, I reduced cloud spend by more than a third!



#### Migrated from bare metal to Cloud

Started from scratch. No more server monkeys! We're in the cloud now!

# **PASSIONS**



**Producing Music** 



Aircraft and Flying



Gaming



**Watching Sport**